[{"id": "58f169b5f7c52aae91cc07d3", "question": "Who played \"Hawkeye\" in the 1970 film \"MASH\"?", "answer": "Donald Sutherland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff2586331a458464a93c465", "question": "Which magazine received a backlash for publishing an April Fool's article entitled \"How to Beat Your Wife Without Leaving Marks\"?", "answer": "Playboy magazine (Romanian edition)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afae", "question": "What first ran from Paddington to Farringdon Street in 1863?", "answer": "The London Underground", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f3057b85aa2bc17b61b2ad3", "question": "What Shakespearean play features the fictional character, Iago?", "answer": "Othello", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b910", "question": "In Cajun cuisine, what crustaceans are playfully referred to as mud bugs?", "answer": "Crawfish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339862", "question": "In Disney's Pinocchio, what colour is the fairy who gives life to Pinocchio?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acbd", "question": "What state saw the start of the American Revolution?", "answer": "Massachusetts", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9f2", "question": "How many US states border an ocean?", "answer": "23", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cd5", "question": "What is the surname of Sesame Street's The Count?", "answer": "Von Count", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e9", "question": "On what TV series did Katie Holmes first achieve stardom from 1998 to 2003?", "answer": "Dawson's Creek", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a518", "question": "Sofia is the capital of which nation?", "answer": "Bulgaria", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5990f916fa5fdd6dd25324f4", "question": "Dendrochronology is better known as what?", "answer": "Ring dating", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339234", "question": "What movie did Ewan McGregor get in character for by shaving his head and shedding 30 pounds?", "answer": "Trainspotting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0e5", "question": "Which pasta is shaped like a bicycle?", "answer": "Biciclette", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600cc8e76de0eb824d405300", "question": "Which borough has New York City's only surf beach?", "answer": "Queens -- Rockaway Beach, just a subway ride away from Manhattan, is the only surf-able beach in NYC limits.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ad8", "question": "In \"The Twelve Days of Christmas\", what did my true love send to me on the sixth day?", "answer": "Six geese-a-laying", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c34f", "question": "What shape is the body of an Erlenmeyer flask?", "answer": "Conical", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd89", "question": "What type of animal is the Japanese monster, Megalon?", "answer": "Beetle", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab7f", "question": "Sierra Leone has direct access to which ocean?", "answer": "Atlantic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c43e", "question": "What name is given to someone who keeps \"apis mellifera\"?", "answer": "Beekeeper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba64", "question": "Which US city is home to the Second City Comedy Troupe?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfdff0eb668d7dfe168b5b3", "question": "In which country is the alcoholic drink Pulque consumed?", "answer": "Mexico", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aa2", "question": "The first album by the Velvet Underground featured what fruit on the cover?", "answer": "A banana", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339091", "question": "In Greek mythology, what was Hades the god of?", "answer": "Underworld", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58b8d7712b42d4a3561a9f0d", "question": "What fast food businessman does Michael Keaton portray in the 2016 film \u201cThe Founder\u201d?", "answer": "Ray Kroc", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b745", "question": "What Biblical name literally means \"the sunny one\"?", "answer": "Samson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fed261bec223966ae8f8908", "question": "In which city was the very first St. Patrick's Day celebration observed?", "answer": "According to a 2017 research by Dr. Michael Francis, the first recorded celebration of St. Patrick's Day in the world was in the city of St. Augustine in the American State of Florida.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7e8", "question": "What is absent in \"negative\" blood types like O negative and AB negative?", "answer": "Rhesus antigens", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58ab960b86faa38a764be51b", "question": "What former republic did the Trabant originate from?", "answer": "East Germany, or German Democratic Republic", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c272", "question": "What is April's birthstone?", "answer": "Diamond", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bee3", "question": "What is the front of a saddle called?", "answer": "Pommel", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339076", "question": "Nut, or Neuth, was the Egyptian goddess of what?", "answer": "Sky", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c03c", "question": "How many stars does the New Zealand national flag have?", "answer": "Four", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c32", "question": "How many seasons did the TV show \"Twin Peaks\" run for?", "answer": "2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe4ee1606d333868d34d773", "question": "Easter comes after how many days of Lent in the Christian calendar?", "answer": "40 days", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3d8a44f0f6af5b06663c", "question": "Who was the original voice of Mickey Mouse?", "answer": "Walt Disney", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f53", "question": "Which US actor is the first to star in 8 consecutive number one hit movies?", "answer": "Will Smith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e92d97ccba3ffe45786bd", "question": "Who wrote the 1932 comic novel \"Cold Comfort Farm\"?", "answer": "Stella Gibbons", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4f", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"THX 1138\"?", "answer": "Maggie McOmie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b35", "question": "What is the name of the winged horse of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Pegasus", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8b0f801dd7bf43be5e78f", "question": "What is Ireland's Christmas monster called?", "answer": "Yule Cat", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c502", "question": "What gas filled the Hindenburg airship?", "answer": "Hydrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388eb", "question": "What is the dot in the \"i\" called?", "answer": "A tittle", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a362", "question": "What US city's skyline boasts the Gateway Arch?", "answer": "St. Louis'", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be71", "question": "What is the Los Angeles Memorial Coliseum also known as?", "answer": "The Grand Old Lady", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66da3a5bfecdd737e08a4", "question": "When is Orthodox Christmas Day?", "answer": "January 7th", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b67e", "question": "How many points must the victor score in a game of cribbage?", "answer": "61 or 121", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b93b", "question": "What month features the harvest moon?", "answer": "September", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af9b", "question": "In which year did the Japanese attack Pearl Harbor?", "answer": "1941", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600cc1e76de0eb824d4052e3", "question": "What islands make up the British Virgin Islands?", "answer": "The British Virgin Islands is a former colony that includes the islands of Virgin Gorda, Tortola, Anegada, and Jost Van Dyke.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a900", "question": "What American street is best known for its eight switchbacks between Hyde and Leavenworth?", "answer": "Lombard Street", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba48", "question": "What US city hosts the world's largest hot air balloon festival?", "answer": "Albuquerque", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133974c", "question": "Who were the winners of the TV show The Amazing Race 18?", "answer": "Jen & Kisha", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60160066fe83fe1f2a824c53", "question": "Saint Valentine is the patron saint of which specific disease?", "answer": "Epilepsy -- Some legends state that he suffered from epilepsy, while others say he cured other people stricken with this ailment.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c03", "question": "What psychologist's autobiography was titled \"Flashbacks\"?", "answer": "Timothy Leary", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a0cf20565ad31a57c79b", "question": "What was the first American war to utilize an early submarine?", "answer": "Revolution War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339419", "question": "What do the letters PJ stand for in PJ Harvey?", "answer": "Polly Jean", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae9552574a5ce6b56b8253", "question": "Which river carved the Grand Canyon?", "answer": "Colorado River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea3728ff048f679a45ab15", "question": "The diameter of an atom is measured in which units?", "answer": "Angstroms", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339228", "question": "What is \"Shawshank\" in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "A prison", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338939", "question": "What annual celebration is taking place at the start of \"Great Expectations\"?", "answer": "Christmas Eve", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a407", "question": "Buffalo Grove is a suburb of what major US city?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dee", "question": "From what language is English has said to borrow the word \"posh\"?", "answer": "Romany", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b323403bf195a31e15d73a1", "question": "How many players are there in a Netball team?", "answer": "Seven", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e44", "question": "What American TV actor plays himself as a fallen angel in Wim Wenders' \"Wings of Desire\"?", "answer": "Peter Falk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59f9bac4364247bf200fb89c", "question": "What is the study of friction called?", "answer": "Tribology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff20ed031a458464a93c42a", "question": "Who was Adolf Hirler's favorite composer?", "answer": "Richard Wagner", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9dc", "question": "What is a group of whales commonly called?", "answer": "Pod", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59f9bae2364247bf200fb89d", "question": "Which creature's name translates as \"the lizard\" in Spanish?", "answer": "Alligator", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8ce", "question": "What is a woolly bear?", "answer": "Caterpillar", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cd610e347d002c297e4ba", "question": "On what date is The Melbourne Cup traditionally held?", "answer": "The first Tuesday of November", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6018bc84d96d05b23b281656", "question": "Who captured and murdered the Inca Emperor Atahualpa?", "answer": "Francisco Pizarro", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d2e", "question": "What is Biff's last name in the \"Back to the Future\" movies?", "answer": "Tannen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389f1", "question": "Who painted the cover art for the 1993 Billy Joel album \"River of Dreams\"?", "answer": "Christie Brinkley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59ded270ea2747c8aff16d3d", "question": "Whose military autobiography was titled \"Crusade in Europe\"?", "answer": "Dwight D. Eisenhower's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ad7ec3bb24f84e0b9f9ffe5", "question": "The \"Atomium\" landmark is located in which country?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601737b944491cbd7c5a178d", "question": "What military leader is believed to have said, \"I can run wild for six months\u00a0... after that, I have no expectation of success\".", "answer": "Japanese Admiral\u00a0Isoroku Yamamoto -- He said this while predicting the future outcome of naval war against the U.S.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fde4966c6c6b019850c9a6f", "question": "Easter was named from what Anglo-Saxon goddess?", "answer": "Eostre", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c14", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the sixth plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Boils", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fdc0f6b469bb8041d07a067", "question": "What is the term for cooking meats like pork or duck in order to melt some of the fat out of them?", "answer": "Rendering", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe65db11f3c0ead6880d61f", "question": "Where was the treaty signed ending the Russo-Japanese War?", "answer": "Portsmouth, New Hampshire", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe6ab5020565ad31a57c828", "question": "Who said, \"Pleasure is the bait of sin\"?", "answer": "Plato", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b1b", "question": "Who employs Alfred Pennyworth as a butler?", "answer": "Bruce Wayne", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3a8fc73aa70ea0b70adf", "question": "What is the oldest city in the world?", "answer": "Damascus (The capital of Syria has evidence of continuous habitation dating back at least 11,000 years)", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b03", "question": "In \"Jurassic Park\", the park is located on an island off the coast of what country?", "answer": "Costa Rica", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c079", "question": "What is the fear of knees known as?", "answer": "Genuphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fd0", "question": "What TV show did \"Fraiser\" spin off from?", "answer": "Cheers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a418", "question": "The Appalachian Trail runs over 2,000 miles from Maine to what southern state?", "answer": "Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ab1b4274fda37788a9a1dc7", "question": "John Simon Ritchie became famous as who?", "answer": "Sid Vicious", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abcb", "question": "Which country does South Africa completely surround?", "answer": "Lesotho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fedd9e06ce05a3942286d7d", "question": "What was the first movie to be rated PG-13?", "answer": "\"Red Dawn\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c9df877e98cb977789fd", "question": "Which European city is known as Auld Reekie?", "answer": "Edinburgh", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3a6", "question": "Who originally designed the Washington Monument?", "answer": "Robert Mills", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e2a", "question": "Which of his ten fingers is God using to give Adam life on the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "His index finger", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ab", "question": "Who does Emma Watson play in the Harry Potter films?", "answer": "Hermione", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dbc", "question": "What holiday is celebrated with an aluminum pole, the Airing of Grievances, and Feats of Strength?", "answer": "Festivus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c888fbde8045e48466db", "question": "What pigment makes plants green?", "answer": "Chlorophyll", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0ae", "question": "Which country hosted the 1982 FIFA World Cup?", "answer": "Spain", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd2d0cf2596a59cbdfbd381", "question": "Who first said, \"When you reach the end of your rope, tie a knot and hang on\"?", "answer": "Abraham Lincoln", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe76aebeec85e375820b2b9", "question": "Including all tereritories, where is the first place to see the sunrise each day in the U.S.?", "answer": "Peacock Point, Wake Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b834", "question": "How many times are Mexican refried beans fried?", "answer": "Once", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5af9874eaeb0982ee4559552", "question": "What is believed to be the first political cartoon published in colonial America?", "answer": "Join or Die Cartoon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7eb1bb24f84e0b9f9ffdb", "question": "What fell into the pool in the film \"Caddyshack\" which caused a major exodus?", "answer": "A Baby Ruth candy bar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a892", "question": "What city is home to the Westminster Clock Tower?", "answer": "London", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc60", "question": "What material is denim made from?", "answer": "Cotton", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015eaf2fe83fe1f2a824bf6", "question": "Which Native American tribe took part in the first Thanksgiving feast?", "answer": "Wampanoag", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b13c", "question": "In what year did Joseph Smith first organize the Mormon Church?", "answer": "1830", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd2", "question": "In biblical etiology, which animal became extinct because it was thrown off the ark and drowned?", "answer": "The unicorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5f9f4d68af848b908361b881", "question": "What was the number of Twitter\u2019s original character limit?", "answer": "140", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96dda23c87fd04dd15e30", "question": "Who was the first U.S. Vice President to resign?", "answer": "John C. Calhoun", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab99d7521a8909e5c332d40", "question": "John \"Jake\" Burns was associated with which British band?", "answer": "Stiff Little Fingers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b23301dd7bf43be5e79b", "question": "What would you \"run up the flagpole\"?", "answer": "An idea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a17b", "question": "What comic strip character is Beetle Bailey's sister?", "answer": "Lois", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3ff", "question": "What is the name of the largest known satellite of Pluto?", "answer": "Charon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5900887ecf842fa4c4ba9689", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"Across the River and into the Trees\"?", "answer": "Ernest Hemmingway", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e9f", "question": "What is the \"Pale Blue Dot\" in the title of Carl Sagan's 1994 book?", "answer": "Earth, as seen from space", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd662c7a5bfecdd737e0848", "question": "What was Princess Diana's title before she married Prince Charles?", "answer": "Lady Diana Spencer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "600b86681d8c1817608d53e4", "question": "What does the \"E\" stand for in Chuck E. Cheese?", "answer": "Entertainment (Restaurant founder, Nolan Bushnell, happens to be the founder of Atari.)", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58ab1884baab681b0929218b", "question": "Which company introduced the Mangusta in the 1960\u2019s?", "answer": "De Tomaso", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fede5766ce05a3942286ded", "question": "What was the first cooking show on television, hosted by James Beard in 1946, called?", "answer": "\"I Love to Eat\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2dc", "question": "What do ladybugs feed on during hibernation?", "answer": "Stored fat", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bbd", "question": "What popular designer was responsible for the wardrobe of \"The Fifth Element\"?", "answer": "Jean Paul Gaultier", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65c401f3c0ead6880d610", "question": "In the Bible, who was the coppersmith that did Paul much evil?", "answer": "Alexander", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5a9e956e7ccba3ffe45786e0", "question": "Anthocyanins are compounds which produce what?", "answer": "Colors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f3058515aa2bc17b61b2ad6", "question": "Who wrote the operas \"The Magic Flute\" and \"The Marriage of Figaro\"?", "answer": "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a74", "question": "What was the name of the high school attended by Archie Andrews and his comic-book friends?", "answer": "Riverdale", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec8a6fec223966ae8f8831", "question": "In the movie \"Polar Express\", there is one rule when it comes to hot chocolate. What is it?", "answer": "Don't let it cool", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008f4fcf842fa4c4ba96ba", "question": "Who released the 1970 album \"After the Gold Rush\"?", "answer": "Neil Young", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c07b", "question": "What is the fear of puppets known as?", "answer": "Pupaphobia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6000ed939a72b906b34e3cee", "question": "What is the name of the apparatus used to measure an unknown electrical resistance by balancing two legs of a circuit?", "answer": "The Wheatstone Bridge, named after its inventor, Sir Charles Wheatstone", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ac", "question": "Where did The Wizard of Oz live?", "answer": "The Emerald City", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b484", "question": "What year was actor Arthur Stanley Jefferson born?", "answer": "1890", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec2", "question": "Who created the Rubik's Cube?", "answer": "Erno Rubik", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6014c48efbde8045e484669d", "question": "What is the name for a group of hyenas?", "answer": "A cackle or clan -- Hyenas are best known for the giggling, yipping sounds they make to express frustration and give warnings.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339170", "question": "What popular Australian pop star sang the words \"All Beauty Must Die\"?", "answer": "Kylie Minogue", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c291", "question": "How many equal sides are there on a scalene triangle?", "answer": "None", "category": "science"}, {"id": "59cdb6d565ff7d326b622a9a", "question": "Who was known as \"The Sultan of Swat\"?", "answer": "Babe Ruth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a77e", "question": "In what direction does the Nile River flow?", "answer": "North", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0ec", "question": "James Todd Smith is the real name of which singer?", "answer": "LL Cool J", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4a3949076251badbeab1", "question": "In which Texas city will you find the famous Alamo?", "answer": "San Antonio -- The old mission was the site of a doomed battle in Texas\u2019s war for independence from Mexico.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d4f", "question": "What year was Canadian author Margaret Atwood born in?", "answer": "1939", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b3232eebf195a31e15d7395", "question": "What movie marked Jodie Foster's directorial debut?", "answer": "Little Man Tate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a776", "question": "What was the nation of Thailand known as prior to 1949?", "answer": "Siam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bacf", "question": "Which sports league awards the Larry O'Brien trophy to the team that wins the yearly Championship?", "answer": "NBA", "category": "general"}, {"id": "592eaec8f83302ff91e4648c", "question": "Mark David Chapman became famous for what in 1980?", "answer": "Shooting John Lennon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "601371c0138175489539638d", "question": "Which musician wrote the theme song for Johnny Carson's \"The Tonight Show\"?", "answer": "Paul Anka -- The song earned him massive royalties. According to Anka, he received $200 every time the song was played.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a966", "question": "What US state was named for the future James II of England?", "answer": "New York", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b3c", "question": "What 2003 Samuel L. Jackson/Colin Farrell movie was based on a mid-1970's  TV show?", "answer": "S.W.A.T.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396cd", "question": "Who is Freakazoid?", "answer": "Dexter Douglas", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58ec25e88dc25ca9e12ef643", "question": "Which former member of Genesis had a hit with \"One More Night\"?", "answer": "Phil Collins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59071dcf3745b36be73039de", "question": "What is the nationality of the first woman in space?", "answer": "Soviet/Russian", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6cc", "question": "A free radical is an atom or molecule that has an odd number of what?", "answer": "Electrons", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b41e", "question": "Who caused the collapse of Barings Bank and inspired the film \"Rogue Trader\"?", "answer": "Nick Leeson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ded148ea2747c8aff16d31", "question": "What Hebrew word means \"so be it\"?", "answer": "Amen", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe523411bf59ab7d2e380ee", "question": "Where was Winona Ryder caught shoplifting?", "answer": "Saks Fifth Avenue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a383", "question": "Where is the Parthenon located?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390bb", "question": "Which English author created Inspector Morse?", "answer": "Colin Dexter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c3b9", "question": "What do most lobsters and crayfish do with their shell after it has molted?", "answer": "Eat it", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a307", "question": "Who played the role of David Duchovny's daughter on the TV show \"Californication\"?", "answer": "Madeleine Martin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5901da79709c1c34536e6eaf", "question": "In ice hockey, how many players for each team are allowed on the ice at the same time?", "answer": "Six", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3af", "question": "Which world champion was beaten by a machine called Deep Blue in 1997?\u00a0", "answer": "Gary Kasparov", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5f9f4c14af848b908361b87e", "question": "What was Google\u2019s original name?", "answer": "BackRub", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe9f090ff048f679a45aa9f", "question": "Samhainophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Halloween", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b90", "question": "What Kenny Rogers song title is his mother's first name?", "answer": "Lucille", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339265", "question": "What was Paul McCartney's Bond theme?", "answer": "Live and Let Die", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5c88e87222f44c2d77a29c47", "question": "Where is the deepest land gorge in the US?", "answer": "Along the border of eastern Oregon, eastern Washington and western Idaho", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5febb7957e83c707845b2131", "question": "The transition of a substance directly from the solid state to the gas state, without passing through the liquid state is called?", "answer": "Sublimation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbaf", "question": "In karate, what color belt is earned just before black?", "answer": "Brown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339afe", "question": "What 1995 Kevin Costner film was the most expensive movie ever made, until \"Titanic\" came along in 1997?", "answer": "Waterworld", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59029f62cad1ec93f27df75f", "question": "What is the thin layer of foam on top of an espresso called?", "answer": "Crema", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a138", "question": "Who sang the theme song to the film \"The Breakfast Club\"?", "answer": "Simple Minds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4c0e49076251badbeacc", "question": "Who got married in the very first White House wedding?", "answer": "Dolley Madison\u2019s sister -- Lucy Payne Washington, the sister of First Lady Dolley Madison, married Thomas Todd in 1819.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6010c9be0775fa611bce67ef", "question": "McDonald\u2019s restaurant periodically runs a themed promotion based on what board game?", "answer": "Monopoly -- Since 1987, McDonald's customers have been hoping to win prizes using game pieces off their soda cups and fries.", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c0a", "question": "What year did Anna Nicole Smith die from a drug overdose?", "answer": "2007", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4a6", "question": "Roadrunners are members of which family of birds?", "answer": "Cuckoos", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5feddaec6ce05a3942286d8a", "question": "Which videogame console did Nintendo release directly prior to the Wii?", "answer": "The GameCube, released in 2001, was the predecessor to the Wii.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51be6ff04d658268c9312", "question": "Who was the husband of the female Judge Deborah in the Bible?", "answer": "Lapidoth", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389f5", "question": "Which Paul McCartney and Wings album includes \"Picasso's Last Words\"?", "answer": "Band on the Run", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d4b", "question": "What actress shaved her head for her role in the movie \"The Passion of Joan of Arc\"?", "answer": "Renee Maria Falconetti", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a17", "question": "Which composer of the \"Rite of Spring\" was still alive to see his music used in Disney's \"Fantasia\"?", "answer": "Igor Stravinsky", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe1f2e9145fb29466707398", "question": "What was the world's first digital quartz watch called?", "answer": "The Pulsar", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b00b", "question": "What duo explored the Pacific Northwest during the early 1800s?", "answer": "Lewis and Clark", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b389", "question": "Guru Nanak founded which religion?", "answer": "Sikhism", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5aab2ea658d116dab4aecb40", "question": "What year was the film \"Honey, I Shrunk the Kids\" released in?", "answer": "1989", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac4d", "question": "What crop failure caused the Irish Famine?", "answer": "Potatoes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acc1", "question": "What is the name of the sonnet by Emma Lazarus that is inside the pedestal of the Statue of Liberty?", "answer": "The New Colossus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b656", "question": "\"Friends of Bill W.\" is another name for what?", "answer": "Alcoholics Anonymous", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600f70f0a9e54d890926f6d9", "question": "Who created the design for Mount Rushmore?", "answer": "Sculptor\u00a0Gutzon Borglum\u00a0created the design and oversaw the project's execution from 1927 to 1941 with his son,\u00a0Lincoln's help.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ba", "question": "How many meters is a lap in an official Olympic swimming pool?", "answer": "100", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395f7", "question": "In The Simpsons episode, \"Treehouse of Horror V,\" what does Homer turn into a time machine?", "answer": "A toaster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a39e", "question": "Which is bigger, the state of Florida or England?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c4dc877e98cb977789a8", "question": "Which US state's motto is \"Live free or die\"?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7d9", "question": "What island nation was ruled by \"Papa Doc\" and \"Baby Doc\" Duvalier?", "answer": "Haiti", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59cdb2dc65ff7d326b622a7a", "question": "Which Apollo space mission put the first men on the moon?", "answer": "Apollo 11", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58ec26578dc25ca9e12ef64a", "question": "How many millimeters are in an inch?", "answer": "25.4", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594d077d1a1c922dd1ac64b9", "question": "What term is used for the speed at which a piece of music is played?", "answer": "Tempo", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339394", "question": "What TV show do Thelma and Louise want to avoid being on?", "answer": "Geraldo", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1a4", "question": "The Sam Maguire Cup is played for in which sport?", "answer": "Gaelic Football", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b195", "question": "Which battle brought the end of Napoleon's European conquests?", "answer": "Battle of Waterloo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2f5", "question": "What is the largest planet in the solar system?", "answer": "Jupiter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af4b", "question": "In what century did the Dodo become extinct?", "answer": "17th", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a332", "question": "What was the name of Ross' pet monkey on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Marcell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c49", "question": "What is Lady Gaga's full name?", "answer": "Stefani Joanne Angelina Germanotta", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21c", "question": "What city was Wild Bill Hickok killed in?", "answer": "Deadwood", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feddd1c6ce05a3942286da0", "question": "Heisenberg is the nickname of the main character in which popular television series?", "answer": "Breaking Bad", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b51b", "question": "What is a Dubbel?", "answer": "A Belgian beer style", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a372", "question": "What is the capital of Iraq?", "answer": "Baghdad", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b639", "question": "What brand of seasoning was named after a famous prime rib restaurant?", "answer": "Lawry's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be53", "question": "Who built the world's first free-standing geodesic dome in 1949?", "answer": "Buckminster Fuller", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd96dac23c87fd04dd15e2d", "question": "Who was the first person to fly around the world alone?", "answer": "Wiley Hardeman Post", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b980", "question": "The Acol system is used in which card game?", "answer": "Bridge", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396eb", "question": "On the Academy Awards statue, what is Oscar standing on?", "answer": "A reel of film", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c15", "question": "According to Exodus, what is the fifth plague of Egypt?", "answer": "Diseased livestock", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd661f6a5bfecdd737e0840", "question": "What country has hosted the most Olympics?", "answer": "USA", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60121c3663c99d48cd169b13", "question": "Normon Rockwell is the official artist of which state?", "answer": "Massachusetts -- He spent 25 years living in the Berkshires of Massachusetts.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d6", "question": "Who played Malcom in the TV show \"Malcom in the Middle\"?", "answer": "Frankie Muniz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b36d01dd7bf43be5e7af", "question": "A clowder is a name given to a group of what?", "answer": "Domestic cats", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5989ad56cb8751d53e7d7610", "question": "What name is shared by an 1849 painting by Asher Durand, and a sculpture situated in Bailick Park in Midleton, Ireland?", "answer": "Kindred Spirits", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015e45afe83fe1f2a824bb1", "question": "Why was the Luftwaffe so ineffective during the last part of the war?", "answer": "Germany was experiencing a severe oil shortage.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac97", "question": "Who was known as the Virgin Queen?", "answer": "Elizabeth I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb01", "question": "What is the chemical element Azote now referred to as?", "answer": "Nitrogen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5a4a94e661d1b4d384d5d673", "question": "Elzie Segar created what popular character?", "answer": "Popeye", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a0a5", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the band \"The Police\"?", "answer": "Sting", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b0c", "question": "What was the name of the shipwrecked boat on \"Gilligan's Island\"?", "answer": "S.S. Minnow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4cc", "question": "What US state capital took its name from the French for \"red stick\"?", "answer": "Baton Rouge", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339553", "question": "Who played Mork and Mindy's baby?", "answer": "Jonathan Winters", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a9e971c7ccba3ffe45786f9", "question": "Melissophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Bees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "597cd9d5e347d002c297e4cf", "question": "What became the tallest building in London after its official opening in October 1965?", "answer": "Post Office Tower", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969a", "question": "The 1975 movie \"The Man Who Would Be King\" is based on the tales of which author?", "answer": "Rudyard Kipling", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8da", "question": "In what country would you find the mouths of the Limpopo river?", "answer": "Mozambique", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338db3", "question": "What famous historical figure turns out to be the disguised Black Knight in Sir Walter Scott's \"Ivanhoe\"?", "answer": "Richard the Lion-hearted", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be73", "question": "What is LP Field also known as?", "answer": "The Woodshed", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcbc", "question": "What model was married to musician Mick Jagger?", "answer": "Jerry Hall", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1a1", "question": "Which staircase in the Leaning Tower of Pisa has fewer steps?", "answer": "The north-facing one", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc16", "question": "What are the official United Nations languages?", "answer": "Arabic, Chinese, English, French, Russian and Spanish", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fffa88473838c5c8a417f3e", "question": "What color is oxygen in liquid or solid form?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c51d", "question": "In the field of medicine, what does MRI stand for?", "answer": "Magnetic Resonance Imaging", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600cc0c66de0eb824d4052db", "question": "In which mountain range can you find Australia\u2019s tallest peak?", "answer": "Australian Alps -- It is covered in ski resorts and in the summer, many people hike to its tallest peak, Mount Kosciuszko.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5b4", "question": "What toy was created 20 years before it hit the public shelves?", "answer": "The RC car", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a070", "question": "Which epic film was based on a novel by Lew Wallace?", "answer": "Ben Hur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e1", "question": "Who sent the 1884 cable that said \"I will not accept if nominated and will not serve if elected\"?", "answer": "William Tecumseh Sherman", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad67", "question": "The original Teamsters union was formed to protect who?", "answer": "Horse carriage drivers", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9d9", "question": "What vitamin deficiency causes Rickets?", "answer": "Vitamin D", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a43", "question": "What Bob Marley song did Eric Clapton cover for a #1 hit?", "answer": "I Shot the Sheriff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391e4", "question": "Whose memory is the movie \"Gladiator\" dedicated to?", "answer": "Oliver Reed's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e147ef76ca6dac04a20ca52", "question": "Who was the first woman to fly solo across the Atlantic Ocean?", "answer": "Amelia Earhart", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60062d69c9d816e292245c32", "question": "Who was the court sculptor of Alexander the Great?", "answer": "Lysippus of Sicyon, in the Peloponnese, was a contemporary of Alexander the Great, who made him his court sculptor.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b21a", "question": "What Labrador retriever supplanted Socks the cat as the Clintons' favorite pet in 1997?", "answer": "Buddy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "590089e6cf842fa4c4ba968d", "question": "What was the first solo album released by Roger Waters?", "answer": "The Pros and Cons of Hitch Hiking", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecc1f1ec223966ae8f8870", "question": "Who\u2019s the only athlete who ever lit the cauldron for an Olympics and then won a gold medal at those same games?", "answer": "Cathy Freeman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391ae", "question": "What is the name of Johnny Depp's character in \"Pirates of the Caribbean\" movie franchise?", "answer": "Jack Sparrow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a26e", "question": "Who won an Oscar as Best Supporting actor in the 1993 film \"The Fugitive\"?", "answer": "Tommy Lee Jones", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a8f", "question": "Orlando Bloom portrayed what character in the 2004 film \"Troy\"?", "answer": "Paris", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba50", "question": "What basketball legend was born Ferdinand Lewis Alcindor?", "answer": "Kareem Abdul-Jabbar", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59e3f4135cb9e8bda6821366", "question": "By what other name is the folk tale \"Cinderella\" also known as?", "answer": "The Little Glass Slipper", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b124", "question": "Which war included an infantry assault known as Pickett's Charge?", "answer": "American Civil War", "category": "history"}]